

# MATEUS FIORI, MSC

## MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

🗣 Avaré-SP - Brazil

**J** +55 (14) 9 8104-7858

in linkedin.com/in/mateusfiori

github.com/mateusfiori

Download PDF

## **Profile**

Machine Learning Engineer with a Master's degree in Computational Intelligence by São Paulo State University (UNESP) with great interest and experience in topics such as NLP, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Software Engineering as a whole. Highly organized and motivated by the countless challenges provided by the area.

## Experience

## Neoway | Uma empresa B3

12/2021 - Atualmente

#### **Machine Learning Engineer**

Implemented MLOps culture inside the Data Science team.

Models and services deployment.

DAG development for data pipeline.

Planned and developed model monitoring structure.

Conducted tech courses for team members.

Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

Clear communication among diverse teams.

## Finch Soluções

06/2020 - Current

#### **Data Scientist**

Planned, developed and maintained data science software services to enhance specific internal processes.

Developed natural language processing and machine/ deep learning models.

Exploratory data analysis.

Conducted tech courses for team members.

Investigated available resources to develop more useful project plans.

Completed reviews of codes, requirements and project plans.

Designed and developed scalable and optimized APIs using Python / FastAPI in order to turn the created models available to external usage.

## New Way Soluções Digitais

05/2019 - 06/2020

## **Software Engineer**

Squad leader.

Planned and developed microservices solution to integrate company's main solution.

Tasks planning and management.

#### New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

## **Full Stack Web Developer**

Developed and maintained features for company's main solution.

Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.

## New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

#### Mentor

Provided guidance on learning Python programming language. Provided exercises and projects to improve learning.

New Way Soluções Digitais

## **Data Classification Supervisor**

03/2018 - 10/2018

Managed 6 people team with the goal of classifying a large amount of natural language data. Data corpus classified successfully.

Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

New Way Soluções Digitais

08/2017 - 03/2018

**Data Classification Intern** 

Data classification in general.

## Jr.com - Empresa Junior de Computação de Bauru

01/2016 - 03/2017

**Vice President** 

Managed a group of student directors.

Created company's legal documentation along with the President.

## Skills

## AI Model Development

Very well experienced on developing a wide variety models to solve business

## System Engineering

Microservice engineering from planning to production, prioritizing organization and clean/intuitive code.

#### Agile

Proven ability and experienced on working in an agile (Scrum) team. Deep understanding of the scrum cerimonies.

## Communication and **Proactivity**

of machine learning

problems.

Oustanding team work ability having empathy and clear communication. Open minded and always open to learn something new.

## Leadership

Comfortable and experienced on having a leading position. Proven ability to work with people. Great active listener.

## Teaching and Learning

Curious and fast learner. Proven ability to teach and/or explain theoretical concepts about software engineering and artificial intelligence.

#### **Technical**

Python	Machine/Deep Learning	REST-RESTful
Docker	Natural Language Processing	Kubernetes
SQL / NoSQL	Linux	Software Design
GIT	Data Science	Airflow

#### Education

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Computer Science

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Master Degree - Computational Intelligence

Mateus Fiori — mateushfiori@gmail.com — +55 (14) 9 8104-7858